<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Programming Pedagogy</title><link>https://jnormile.github.io/research-notebook/</link><description>Recent content on Programming Pedagogy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 12:07:03 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jnormile.github.io/research-notebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dynamic</title><link>https://jnormile.github.io/research-notebook/posts/dynamic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 12:07:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jnormile.github.io/research-notebook/posts/dynamic/</guid><description>Text here</description></item><item><title>Questions</title><link>https://jnormile.github.io/research-notebook/posts/questions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 12:07:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jnormile.github.io/research-notebook/posts/questions/</guid><description>How do we effectively teach entirely new ways of thinking&amp;ndash;like teaching someone who&amp;rsquo;s never seen a terminal window to write their first few lines of code? What practices and behaviors are useful for meaningfully maximizing our time spent grappling with and learning a complex concept&amp;ndash;like a heady algorithm that seems all but impenetrable at first glance?
Questions like these drive my research into pedagogy as it pertains to the science and art of programming, a craft that&amp;rsquo;s quickly become very personal for me.</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://jnormile.github.io/research-notebook/posts/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 12:07:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jnormile.github.io/research-notebook/posts/about/</guid><description>My name is Jeff Normile and I&amp;rsquo;m a student at Allegheny College pursuing an education in both Computer Science and Communications.
As can be inferred from the sidebar, I have a particular interest in the way we learn. I think it behooves any student to think critically about the ways in which they process and synthesize new information into usable, actionable knowledge, though this feels especially important for myself: after a decade in the workforce I decided to pivot and make the return to academia, so coming from a decade of my time being money has led me to constantly evaluate the value of my time in the classroom.</description></item></channel></rss>